# **Oleksandr Stasyev**

Holly Springs, NC <u>LinkedIn</u>

#### SKILL SUMMARY

- 2+ years of software development experience
- 2 years of experience with Java and API development/testing (including Postman)
- 2 years of experience with debugging
- 1 year of experience with complex SQL queries for identifying data problems
- Knowledge of JSON
- Bachelor's degree in Computer Science from University of North Carolina at Charlotte (UNCC)

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with 2+ years of well-rounded experience at Fidelity Investments and excellent communication skills.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Java, SQL, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Python, C++, XML

Technologies: JUnit testing, Spring, Postman, Git, Jenkins, Jira, Maven, npm, Splunk, Vue.js, Angular 2, Figma

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **Fidelity Investments, Remote**

01/2021 - 02/2022

### **Software Engineer**

- Managed and developed new APIs using Java/Spring
- Wrote complex SQL queries to service data incorrectly calculated by APIs
- Followed Test-Driven Development to implement new features
- Debugged existing codebase to pinpoint incorrect data processing
- Serviced user data in different PostgreSQL database environments
- Created RESTful services with Spring Boot framework
- Improved existing technical documentation
- Installed and deployed apps using CI/CD pipeline

### Fidelity Investments, NC

05/2017 - 08/2020

#### Technical Summer Intern (Multiple Engagements)

- Collaborated with another intern to improve in house mobile app using lonic
- Researched and implemented new methods of processing data using TypeScript
- Developed a generic component for the company website
- Created a dashboard using Angular 6 and Bootstrap
- Worked with Postman to test API endpoints
- Automated repository downloads with Python
- Evaluated IT monitoring systems for the team
- Applied Agile methodology and Scrum practices to daily tasks
- Engagements during this period: May 2017 Aug 2017, May 2018 Aug 2018, May 2019 Aug 2019, Jun 2020 Aug 2020

Curu, Remote 09/2018 – 12/2018

### Web Development Intern

- Maintained company website with Flask framework
- Improved web-app security by implementing 2FA in registration
- Enhanced security level during password reset by implementing 2FA
- Developed HTML pages based on designer wireframes
- Built a responsive web page using Flexbox, HTML, CSS with preprocessing

Cary Coder School, NC 02/2017 - 05/2017

#### **Code Coach**

Computer science tutor

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Graduation Year 2020 The University of North Carolina at Charlotte (UNCC)

# **PROJECTS**

### Capstone:

• Developed a storytelling web app using MEVN stack and GPT-3 API

### Java:

• Hill Cipher program in Java to encrypt and decrypt messages using matrices

## Image Processing:

• Given pixel values output an actual image using Python

#### Personal Website:

• Written in plain HTML, JS with SCSS preprocessor